xoom.com 2016-11-05

# Privacy Policy | Xoom, a PayPal Service

Effective Date: **2016-10-03**

PayPal, Inc. takes your privacy very seriously. This Privacy Policy applies to Xoom’s websites (for purposes of this Privacy Policy, " **websites** " includes www.xoom.com, our mobile websites, and our mobile applications) and the services associated with it (" **Xoom** " or " **the Service** "). This Privacy Policy applies only to the Service and does not apply to the practices of any other PayPal service. Terms used but not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings assigned to them in our User Agreement. 

We are committed to protecting our customers' privacy and security. This Privacy Policy explains what personal information we collect about you, with whom we share it, and how you (the user of the Service) can direct us not to share certain information with certain parties. **"Personal Information"** refers to information that can be used to identify an individual. You should read this Privacy Policy in its entirety. Certain sections may apply differently to residents of different jurisdictions.

[ Truste ](https://privacy.truste.com/privacy-seal/Xoom-Corporation/validation?rid=082b03b6-0dbf-45de-b8b4-3d73247810ba "TRUSTe online privacy certification") The Xoom websites have been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this Privacy Policy and its practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy_seals_and_services/consumer_privacy/privacy-programs-requirements.html) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your Personal Information. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through www.xoom.com, our mobile websites, and our mobile applications. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. For more information on our certification, please click on the TRUSTe seal.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact us. If you are not satisfied with our response you can please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

* We may collect the following information about you, your Recipient, your Sender, or your Beneficiary, which may include non-public Personal Information:

  * Information that you provide us in the course of using the Service, such as your name, mailing address, email address, and telephone number(s). We may also collect certain sensitive information from you including your bank account number, credit or debit card number, date of birth and social security number; 
  * Information that you provide us in the course of your participation in various partner promotional programs; 
  * To facilitate our Service, we request certain third party Personal Information from you  or your mobile device's address book, such as your Beneficiary, Sender's or Recipient's full name, mailing address, email address, and telephone number. We may also collect from you sensitive financial information of a Beneficiary or a Recipient, including billing account numbers and account balances held at Service Companies, and bank account and routing numbers; 
  * Information about your usage of the Service, including your Transaction history, how you use the Service to send or receive Transactions, and to and for whom you send Transactions; 
  * Information that we lawfully obtain from third parties, such as Service Companies, identity verification services, electronic database services, and credit reporting agencies; 
  * Information that we indirectly obtain from you, such as information about the device, hardware and software you use when accessing the Service, your IP address, the pages you access on our websites, and other websites that you visit prior to accessing the Service. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this for fraud prevention, to improve our Service, and to improve our marketing, analytics, or website functionality; 
  * Recordings of your communications with our Customer Service department, including telephone calls and electronic communications; and 
  * Type of device you use, operating system version, and the device identifier. 

We do not ask you for, access or track any location-based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our mobile applications or Service.

We may occasionally send you push notifications through our mobile applications to send you marketing messages and other Service or Transaction-related notifications that may be of importance to you. You may at any time opt-out from receiving these types of communications by turning them off at the device level through your settings or through the mobile application settings.

We and our third-party service providers, including our marketing partners and analytics providers, may also use cookies, web beacons, tags, scripts and similar technology ("Cookies"). Cookies are small data files that are placed on your computer or mobile device to, among other things, administer the website, track and analyze trends in your use of our websites, remember your preferences when you return to the website and gather information about our users as a whole. The information we store in the Cookies we place may include your email address in addition to non-Personal Information. We may receive reports from third-party service providers based on their use of Cookies about our users on an individual or aggregated basis.

You are free to decline the Cookies we place if your browser permits, but doing so may interfere with your use of the Service. The use of Cookies by our third-party service providers is not covered by this Privacy Policy. You are free to decline these Cookies if your browser permits. We do not have access or control over these Cookies. In addition, some of our third party advertising vendors or partners show our ads on sites across the Internet. These vendors or partners may use Cookies to gather information about your activities on our website and other websites in order to serve you advertising based on your browsing activities. We do not necessarily have access to or control over the Cookies they use, but you may be able to opt-out of some of their practices by visiting: <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/> or <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. Please note that opting out does not prevent the display of advertisements to you.

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include your internet protocol (IP) address, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. From time to time, we may combine this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you for reasons such as analysis, security, content generation or marketing.

We may use the MixPanel analytics tool in order to develop and analyze use of the Service. Analytics companies may access anonymous data (such as your identifier for advertising or device identifier) to help us understand how the Service is used. They use this data on our behalf and do not use this data for their own purposes except in aggregate form; they do not share data as to any individual user except in limited circumstances. If you wish to opt-out from MixPanel analytics, please follow this link: <https://mixpanel.com/optout/>.

We may use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our mobile software on your mobile device. This software may record information such as how often you use the mobile applications, the events that occur within the mobile applications, aggregated usage, performance data, and from where the mobile application was downloaded. We may link the information we store within the analytics software to any Personal Information you submit within the mobile applications.

We currently do not recognize "do-not-track" signals from your browser. We engage third parties, such as marketing or analytics partners, who may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use our websites. We use local storage objects, such as Flash Cookies ( **"LSOs"** ) and Local Storage, such as HTML5, to prevent unauthorized or fraudulent sign ups. Third parties, with whom we partner to provide certain features on our websites or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity also use Flash Cookies and HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs. To manage Flash LSOs please click here: <http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html>. Disabling LSOs may affect the performance of our Service.

* We collect information for the following purposes:

  * To process your Transactions;
  * To verify your identity;
  * To collect payment for your use of the Service;
  * To allow our partners to fulfill their promotional obligations to you;
  * To troubleshoot problems with the Service;
  * To comply with applicable laws, regulations, and rules, such as those relating to "know-your-customer" and anti-money laundering requirements;
  * To detect and prevent fraud and other illegal uses of the Service; and
  * To send you marketing notices, service updates, and promotional offers.

We will retain your account information, including but not limited to your payment source information and Personal Information about you, your Recipient, or your Beneficiary, as needed to provide you Service, as required by applicable law, to resolve disputes and to enforce our agreements. Xoom abides by strict security standards, but if you wish to cancel your account and stop using Xoom's Service, contact us at https://www.xoom.com/contact-xoom-customer-service. We will continue to retain your account information after your account is cancelled as required under applicable law, regulations, and rules. 

* We do not sell or rent the information we collect to third parties for their promotional purposes unless we receive your permission to do so. Nevertheless, we may share information about you, your Recipient, or your Beneficiary (including nonpublic, Personal Information) with:

  * Members of or divisions within the PayPal corporate family, such as PayPal, Venmo, or Braintree as necessary to provide you with the Service, to provide joint content, products, and services (such as registration, transactions, and customer support), to help detect and prevent potentially illegal acts and violations of our policies, and to guide decisions about their products, services, and communications. 
  * Third-party service providers under contract with PayPal, Inc or its affiliates that help us with our business operations, such as transaction processing, fraud prevention, and marketing. We share your Personal Information with these companies only as necessary to provide you with our Service; 
  * Third-parties that we partner with to offer additional products and services, such as long-distance telephone minutes, gift cards or loyalty points, but only when you elect to participate and/or to receive information about those additional products and services. If you do not want us to share your Personal Information with these partners, contact us at https://www.xoom.com/contact-xoom-customer-service; 
  * In the event of the sale, acquisition or merger of some or all of our assets, Personal Information about you, your Recipient or your Beneficiary might be a part of the transferred assets. We shall notify you in the event of such an occurrence and inform you of any choices you may have regarding your Personal Information, by placing a notice on our websites; and 
  * Law enforcement, government officials or other third parties, but only 
    * in connection with a formal request, subpoena, court order, or similar legal procedure; or 
    * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, prevent physical harm or financial loss, report suspected illegal activity, or to investigate violations of our User Agreement. 

Our websites offer publicly accessible blogs. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. Please do not post any information you prefer to keep private, including but not limited to your email address, mailing address, or Xoom Transaction information.

* If your personal information changes, or if you no longer wish to use our Service, you can access, modify, delete or update your Personal Information submitted on our websites by logging in to your account and changing your preferences or by contacting Xoom Customer Service at 1-877-815-1531. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

* We employ industry-accepted standards in protecting the information you submit to us on our websites. We have put in place SSL [Secure Socket Layer] encryption technology to protect your sensitive information transmitted on our websites. We also require a username and password from each user who wants to access his or her information on our websites. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

* Federal and state laws allow you to restrict the sharing of your Personal Information in certain instances. However, these laws also state that you cannot restrict other types of sharing.

  * If, after giving us your permission to share your Personal Information with third parties with whom we market our jointly offered products, you later decide that you no longer want us to share such information, you may contact us by email at https://www.xoom.com/contact-xoom-customer-service; fax at 415-777-8690; or by mail at Xoom Customer Service, 425 Market Street, 12th Floor, San Francisco, CA 94105-5404, USA. 
  * You may also opt-out from promotional email messages to you or your blog subscription by accessing your Email Preferences under "My Account" or selecting the "Unsubscribe" function present in each promotional or blog email message we send out and providing the required information or you may contact us at https://www.xoom.com/contact-xoom-customer-service. 

* If you have a complaint, first contact **Xoom Customer Service at 1-877-815-1531**. If you are a Texas resident and you still have an unresolved complaint regarding PayPal, Inc.’s money transmission activity, including Xoom, a PayPal Service, please direct your complaint to: Texas Department of Banking: 2601 North Lamar Boulevard; Austin, Texas 78705; 1-877-276-5554 (toll free); [www.dob.texas.gov](http://www.dob.texas.gov/) or email [consumer.complaints@dob.texas.gov](mailto:consumer.complaints@dob.texas.gov). 

* Our websites contain links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these other websites. We encourage you to familiarize yourself with the privacy practices of these other websites prior to engaging with them or submitting your Personal Information to them.

Our websites include social media features, such as the Facebook Like button, and widgets, such as the Share button or interactive mini-programs that run on our websites. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our websites, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our websites. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

* If you choose to use our Refer a Friend program to tell a friend about our Service, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the websites. We store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our Refer a Friend program. Your friend may request removal from our Refer a Friend program by following the instructions in the promotional email message we send out and providing the required information. 

* If you choose to use our Service to send a request for a Transaction, we will ask you for your prospective Sender’s email address for the purpose of sending your email request to your prospective Sender through the websites. We store your prospective Sender’s information for the sole purpose of sending your email request and tracking the success of our request service. Your prospective Sender may request removal from our request service by following the instructions in the email message we send out and providing the required information.

* You can import contacts from your Outlook or other email account address book in connection with using our Service. We collect the username and password for the email account from which you import your contacts and will only use it for that purpose. We may also collect the name, mailing address, email address, and telephone number(s) of any contacts that you import in order to facilitate the Service. 

* We may amend this policy at any time, and shall notify you by posting a revised version on our websites. Should we make a substantial change to the manner in which we collect, use, or store Personal Information about you, your Recipient, or your Beneficiary, we shall provide prior notice on our websites, or by email.

*
